Imagine a skill acquisition spectrum
which spans from being a complete novice
to the point of true mastery.
When you encounter a new task or challenge,
something you don't know how to tackle yet,
first set a learning intention.
For example,
to experiment with a new project management tool,
or even learn to play a new instrument.
In these early stages of learning,
you shouldn't fixate on how well you're doing.
Instead, focus on the quality of your learning.
When you decide to take up a new skill,
you may set performance goals too early in the process,
and when you fail to achieve them,
you feel overwhelmed and even give up.
But don't fall into that trap.
Meet Paula.
She loves playing the piano,
and her dream is to play a piece with her friends.
So she sets a learning intention:
learn how to play the piano so that she can
begin learning a piece with her friend,
because before she can consider setting a performance goal,
like performing with her friends in front of guests,
she will need to practice with purpose and focus in order to develop
the dexterity and speed required to play the piano.
Once you practice sufficiently
and continue to develop your skills,
you can then apply your learning
and introduce performance goals.
In the workplace, the distinction between setting
a learning intention and a performance goal
would look something like this.
“Increase sales revenue by 10% this year”
is a performance goal.
It's not something you would set unless
you were already competent in your sales skills.
This is where starting with a learning intention would help.
For example,
taking the time to deepen your expertise
about one of your company's new offerings,
or practicing your customer talking points with colleagues.
With that solid foundation, you'll be equipped
to eventually meet the challenge of a performance goal.
Whether it's learning to play the piano
or something much simpler,
you'll know you are ready to perform when you feel
excited to demonstrate what you've learned.
And if you find yourself somewhere
in between on the learning spectrum,
you can set a mix of learning intentions
and performance goals.
In our rapidly changing world,
there is an increasing number of opportunities to grow and learn.
Whether you find yourself exploring new roles or taking on
new responsibilities as part of your existing role,
you will set yourself up for long-term performance and success
when you start by setting learning intentions.